

MUHAMMAD AMIR HAMZAH

Aspiring Data Analyst

+6018-910 3791

amiriium381@gmail.com

Bukit Katil, Melaka

in www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-amir-hamzah 🔗 amoiiir.github.io

ABOUT ME

A student specializing in Business Intelligence and Analytics, possessing experience in analytical and technical skills within the Information Technology field, seeks an internship placement in data analytics or **information technology** to enhance future growth in the IT domain.

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Information Technology International Islamic University Malaysia 2020 - 2024 (expected)

Foundation in Information Technology International Islamic University Malaysia 2019 - 2020

Sijil Pelajaran Malaysia (SPM) Maktab Rendah Sains Mara

2014 - 2018

CGPA: 3.70



CGPA: 3.33



SPM: 5As



Analytical Skills

- Microsoft Excel
- Data Visualizations
- Tableau
- Data Cleaning
- SQL
- Statistics and Analytics

Other Skills & IT Languages

- Flutter & Firebase
- Adobe Photoshop
- Web Development
- R & Python
- Data Warehousing
- Project Management

Languages

- English
- Bahasa Malaysia Arabic

PROJECTS

SwitchAR: AR Virtual Switch Control For IoT-based Smart Home Automation 2023

- · A partnered Final Year Project that aims to help the elderly to become more independent when interacting with home appliances.
- Proposed solution by developing a mobile application using Flutter and Unity application that implements the concepts of Internet of Things (IoT) and Augmented Reality (AR).

Tools used:









Blynk

Arduino IDE

Vuforia

Crime Dataset Analysis 2023

- Coordinated a group of four people to investigate the crime rate in Malaysia from the year 2015 until 2020.
- Provided insights on the trends of crime rate through visualizations and interactive dashboards.
- Eased the audience to understand the trends of crime rates in Malaysia with the use of data visualizations.

Tools used:





Tableau

Microsoft Excel

Covid-19 Data Cleaning 2023

- · Self-learned project data cleaning basics using SQL Server through a YouTube course.
- Utilized data sourced from https://ourworldindata.org/covid-deaths to clean and transform raw data into a structured format suitable for visualization purposes.

Tools used:



Standard Query Language



SQL Server Management Studio

WORKING EXPERIENCE



Internship - Programmer

March 2024 - Present

Wahdah Technologies

- Contributed to the development of a mobile application by enhancing existing features.
- Acquired proficiency in utilizing RESTful APIs and Android Studio to fulfill assigned tasks for the company.

LEADERSHIP

KPMG Student Ambassadors 2023

January 2023 - December 2023



- Strategized engaging physical and virtual events to facilitate connections between IIUM students and KPMG mentors.
- Executed workshops aimed at enhancing students' job market competitiveness.
- Achievement: managed to gather 30 to 40 students to a physical event in IIUM.



ICT Student Society Committee 2022

September 2022 - January 2023

- Volunteered to be part of committee member of ICT Student Society 2022/2023, contributing to various student activities.
- Managed the arrangement of the venue and equipment for upcoming events, ensuring a seamless and successful execution.

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATES

Malaysia Data Innovation Talent 2023

- Participant won top 50 among 120 groups in national level.
- Analyzed datasets from openDOSM related to housing affordability across income groups and provide solutions through dashboards and analytics.

Final Year Project - 1st Place in System Development Category

 Awarded 1st place in the System Development category for the Final Year Project from department of KICT.

Dean's List Award

- Semester 1 and 2, 2020/2021
- Semester 1 and 2, 2022/2023
- Semester 1 and 2, 2023/2024

Program Pemantapan Bahasa, Sesi 2022/2023

- Competed in a university-level challenge, presenting innovative traffic improvement solutions for the IIUM.
- Secured a fifth-place ranking out of nine participants.

Kaggle

Intro to Programming in Python

REFERENCES

Dr. Zainatul Shima Abdullah

IAP Coordinator IIUM

Department of Information System,

Kulliyyah of Information & Communication Technology, International Islamic University Malaysia,

shima@iium.edu.my

Dr. Madihah Bt. S. Abd. Aziz

Deputy Director, Centre for Professional Development, Department of Information System,

Kulliyyah of Information & Communication Technology, International Islamic University Malaysia,

madihahs@iium.edu.my